# Irene Smith

845-699-2258 • irenesmith13@gmail.com http://www.irenesmith.com • @Story Teller

## **Summary**

Hybrid developer/technical writer, with over 30 years' experience with multiple programming languages and technologies. Comfortable with full stack development of both native applications for Windows as well as website and web-based applications. Extensive experience writing API documentation, design and requirement documents, and release notes.

### **Technical Skills**

**Application Development**: C# and VB.NET, VBA, Python

Web Development: HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap, ASP.NET, ASP 3.0

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft Access, MongoDB

Graphics and Video: Adobe PhotoShop, PaintShop Pro, Gimp, Microsoft Visio, Snaglt, OBS Studio,

Adobe After Effects, DaVinci Resolve

Source Control: Git, Perforce, Visual Source Safe (VSS), SVN, Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Development Tools: Sublime Text 3, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, PyCharm

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), DOS, macOS

## **Professional Experience**

#### Google, Inc.

**Technical Writer IV (Contract)** 

8/2023 - 2/2024

#### Responsibilities

- Write documentation for Google Material Design 3
- Manage current documentation set for Material Design 3.
- Expand content for developer documentation for the Google Material 3/Wiz components.

#### **Amazon Web Services**

Code Example Developer (SDE)

9/2020 - 4/2023

### Responsibilities

- Develop C# code examples for the AWS SDK for .NET.
- Participated in an initiative to simplify the inclusion of code examples in developer documentation by including specialized comments in the code.
- Developed scenario applications that perform basic tasks for a single AWS service, and crossservice code examples, applications that use multiple AWS services, usually in the form of an ASP .NET application with a React.js front-end.
- Act as on call for the code examples build process which includes creating test builds on a virtual desktop, then initiating the actual build process on the build servers, and then trouble-shooting any problems that arise.

#### Mozilla

## **Firefox Developer Content Manager (Contract)**

6/2018 - 11/2019

#### Responsibilities

- Manage content for MDN Web Docs Browser Extensions and Firefox Developer Tools
- Write tutorials for web development.
- Update and refine existing content to reflect new and updated Firefox features and web development best practices.
- Create example code for tutorials and web APIs.

Resume of Irene Smith Page 2

## **MongoDB**

Technical Writer 9/2017 – 3/2018

Responsibilities

- Wrote documentation for MongoDB Atlas
- Collaborated with developers to document new features of MongoDB.
- Created web documentation for MongoDB using restructured Text (reST) and Sphinx.

### **Moody's Analytics**

Technical Writer (Contract)

11/2016 - 6/2017

Responsibilities

- Worked with developers to create technical documentation for Cloud Computing Project
- Created stylesheets and documentation templates.
- Helped define processes for support, development, and technical documentation projects.
- Created quick guides, workflows, and high-level overviews for end users.

### Credit Suisse, New York, NY

Technical Writer (Contract)

5/2016 - 9/2016

Responsibilities

- Interviewed Developers to create technical documentation for CCAR Application Modules
- Helped to create SAD (Software Architecture Documentation) document for CCAR Application
- Created data flow and architectural diagrams and application screenshots.
- Wrote reference materials for use by support personnel in application troubleshooting.

### **BNP Paribas, New York, NY**

**Developer (Contract)** 

6/2015 - 12/2015

Responsibilities

- Wrote C# console applications that are run as automated processes to update trade data.
- Created VBA Scripts for Microsoft Excel that create reports for traders.
- Enhanced the UI of a stock pricing application that uses MVC, Angular, and Bootstrap
- Wrote, reviewed, and edited project requirements and user stories.

#### **TIAA-CREF, Charlotte, NC (Remote)**

Senior Technical Writer (Contract)

11/2013 - 2/2015

Responsibilities

- Create and maintain templates and VBA macros to simplify document creation.
- Create and update the Developer's Reference for the PRISM API, an application that uses Oracle coherence to cache mainframe data for a Java API
- Create and update a data dictionary for use by PRISM developers.
- Create and update walkthroughs for the PRISM application that include step-by-step instructions and screenshots.

## Google, Inc., New York, NY 10011

Technical Writer III (Contract)

7/2012 - 7/2013

Responsibilities

- Wrote technical guides and other documentation using HTML5, CSS3, and markdown.
- Wrote and maintained API documentation for the following Ad Exchange technologies: Buyer REST API, Seller REST API, Buyer SOAP API, Real-time Bidding Protocol
- Wrote the developer's guide for Google's open-source project, Open Bidder

## Medidata Solutions, Inc. New York, NY 10003

Senior Programming Technical Communicator Senior Technical Communicator, **Team Lead**  1/2010 - 1/2012

1/2008 - 1/2010

**Technical Communicator** 

9/2006 - 1/2008

Resume of Irene Smith Page 3

## Responsibilities

- Scrum Master for internal tools for the Technical Communications department
- Used C# to develop ASP .NET applications, Windows applications, and Microsoft Word add-ins. These tools reduced document preparation time from days to minutes
- Used SQL Server to design and create database model for all internal tools including table design, stored procedures, and functions.
- Lead and mentored, and trained colleagues in creating design specifications and requirements.
- Team Lead for multiple documentation projects.

#### Times Herald Record, Middletown, NY 10940

Paginator, Assistant Obituary Editor

2/2005 - 1/2006

#### Responsibilities

- Developed a set of Microsoft Word macros to automate the process preparing obituaries, thus reducing preparation time from over half an hour to less than one minute.
- Documented obituary and classified preparation procedures.
- Prepared obituaries and classified advertising for printing.

#### Microsoft, Redmond, WA 98052

Programming Writer (FTE), SQL Server Group

4/2000 - 10/2003

## Responsibilities

- Developed samples for the **System.Data** namespace of the .NET Framework for versions 1.0, 1.1, and 2.0 using C# and VB .NET to create console and ASP .NET applications.
- Used C++, Visual Basic 6.0, Java (Microsoft J++), JavaScript, and VBScript to develop console application examples for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references.
- Developed examples for Microsoft XML using C++ and Visual Basic

#### mpl2.com, Bellevue, WA

Programming Writer (on contract at Microsoft)

8/1999 - 3/2000

Originally called Meridian Partners, Ltd., mpl2.com placed writers in contract positions at various locations in Redmond, Bellevue, and Seattle including Microsoft.

#### Responsibilities

- Wrote conceptual and API reference documentation for Microsoft's database objects.
- Used C++, Jscript, Visual Basic 6.0, VBScript, and Java to develop ASP 3.0 and console example applications for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references.

#### **Solo Game Development**

Designed, coded, created graphics, and wrote context-sensitive help files for several Microsoft Windows commercial game packages:

- Casino Nights (Craps, Roulette, Black Jack, and Video Poker)
- **Dice Games** (Crag, Over 'n Under, and Bird Cage)
- Solitaire (Pyramid and Golf)

## **Education**

University of Phoenix, Online

BS Information Technology/Software Design

Orange County Community College, Middletown, NY

AA, Liberal Arts